localwiki.org 2016-04-02

# Privacy Policy - Guide - LocalWiki

LocalWiki is committed to preserving your privacy and being transparent about how we use information collected through LocalWiki.org (the “Website”) and any other applications, functionality, or services offered by LocalWiki (collectively with the Website, the “Services”). This Privacy Policy describes how LocalWiki uses, collects, and shares information collected through the Services. By using the Services, you agree to and accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post changes on this page so be sure to check back regularly. We will also notify you by posting an announcement on the Website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. Continuing to use our Services after any changes have been posted, constitutes your acceptance of any modifications to the Terms.

##  **1.   Contributions**

**1.1 Public Content.** In general, all content (pages, maps, files, etc.) on LocalWiki is public, including any contributions made by LocalWiki community members.  The history of every edit to content made through the Services is publicly displayed and retained indefinitely by LocalWiki. Even if an article is "deleted," a website administrator or volunteer may still see what was removed from public view. Aside from the rare times when LocalWiki is required to delete editing-history in response to a court order or legal process, there is no guarantee that permanent deletion will occur.

**1.2 Individual Contributions.** If you contribute or edit content on through the Services (“Contributions”), your Contributions will be visible to the public and may show up in search results of third-party search engines.  If you have registered an account with LocalWiki, your Contributions will be associated with your username.  If you have not registered with LocalWiki, your Contributions will be associated with your IP Address.

##  **2.** **Information Collected by LocalWiki**

As part of the Services, we may collect the following types of information from you when you use the Services (“User Information”):

**2.1** **Registration Information.** In order to access certain portions of the Services you must complete a registration form. In this registration form, we collect certain personal information, such as your email address, username and password.  Your email address will remain private, unless choose to post it on public facing portions of the Services, such as your profile page or the Contributors Page.  Please use discretion on what you choose to post on public facing portions of the Services, as it will be available to the public and may show up in search results of third-party engines.

**2.2 Username.** You will also be asked to create a username, which will be used to identify when you are logged onto the Services, and to identify your Contributions to the Services. Again, your username will be visible to the public, and may show up in search results of third-party search engines.

**2.3** **Optional user information:** As a registered user, you may choose to share more details publicly. You may provide your name, a personal website, share your email address, and talk about yourself on your profile page. Please use discretion on what you choose to post on public facing portions of the Services, as it will be available to the public and may show up in search results of third-party engines. If provided, your name may be used to identify your Contributions to the Service, and may be used by third parties as a means to attribute your contributions.

**2.4 Usage Information.** LocalWiki may collect certain usage data, such as your IP address, URL request, browser type, and the date and time of a request. LocalWiki may use cookies (as further described below) or other automated mechanisms to collect this information and may collect this information on an aggregate or individual basis. LocalWiki uses this information to help administer, manage and improve the Services, prevent abuse, analyze trends, and to tailor your user experience. In addition, LocalWiki may use anonymized usage statistics that may be derived from this information for marketing, research or reporting purposes. Please note that Contributions made by unregistered users will be identified by that user’s IP Address.

##  **3.** **Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that LocalWiki can send to your browser for storage on your computer. Cookies make using the Services easier by saving your status and preferences and refreshing them every time you use the Services. For instance, LocalWiki may use cookies to recognize you when you return to the Services so that you do not have to resubmit your log-in credentials. In order to clear this logon information, for example if using a public terminal, you should log out of your account. While many browsers allow you to change your settings in order to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent, LocalWiki recommends that you leave cookies enabled, as disabling cookies may prevent you from using and may interfere with some functionality of the Services.

##  **4\. Archiving**

LocalWiki may retain User Information collected through the Services indefinitely for restorative, archival, or research purposes.

##  5\. Email Communications

LocalWiki may send you emails containing LocalWiki-related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions. You may also receive notification emails from LocalWiki to inform you of changes in the Services, new service offerings or other information related to your use of the Services. If you do not want to receive promotional emails from LocalWiki, please visit your User Settings page or follow the opt-out instructions contained in email messages you receive from us. However, please note that, even if you choose not to receive marketing emails from LocalWiki, you will continue to receive all emails related to your use of the Services (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords) from LocalWiki.

##  **6.** **Sharing of** **Information** **with** **Third Parties**

Generally, LocalWiki does not share User Information with third parties without your consent. Nonetheless, in order to maximize your user experience on the Services, the following individuals or entities may have access to User Information:

##  **6.1 LocalWiki Personnel**

LocalWiki personnel and a small number of vetted volunteer may have access to User Information as necessary for LocalWiki to operate its business and to provide you the Services.

**6.2 Third Party Service Providers**. LocalWiki may share User Information with its third party service providers as necessary for those third party service providers to provide services to LocalWiki.

**6.3 Business Transfers**. If LocalWiki is acquired by or LocalWiki otherwise transfers and/or sells substantially all of its assets to another company, LocalWiki will transfer any User Information it has in its possession to the other company as part of the sale or transfer of the company or assets.

**6.4 Protection of LocalWiki and Others**. We may share User Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a governmental or court order; to comply with applicable law; to comply with a subpoena from a third party; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of LocalWiki, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection.

**6.5 Data Analysis**. LocalWiki may use, transfer, and share aggregated, anonymous data derived from User Information with researchers, journalists, funders and other third parties that LocalWiki may choose to work with. This data will not include any personally identifiable information.

##  **7.** **Children**

Generally, you must be at least 13 years old to use the Services. However, we encourage schools and teachers to use LocalWiki responsibly with youth to engage in their local communities. If you are a school or teacher, you represent and warrant that you have obtained all necessary consents pursuant to local and federal privacy law in order for your students to interact with and use the Services.  If you are a parent and become aware that your child has been using the Services outside of the supervision of a school or teacher, please let us know and we will remove your child’s information.

##  8\. Transfer of Information Across Borders

Your information may be transferred to, and maintained on, servers and databases located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as your jurisdiction. Please be advised that we may transfer your information to and from any state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction, and process it in the United States or elsewhere. By using the Services, you consent to any such transfer of your information. 

##  Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of 2014-10-22.
